prodesigntools.com 2019-06-29

# Privacy Policy | ProDesignTools

Thank you for visiting our website. The privacy of our customers is important to us, and our Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect and use the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site and our products and services.

Importantly, we never sell, rent, or share your personal information with any third parties, unless exceptionally required by law.

## What Information Do We Collect?

When you visit our website you may provide us with two types of information: (1) optional personal information you choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis, which is used solely for correspondence you have specifically requested or regarding comments you have expressly left, and (2) website usage information that is collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our site, which is used solely to measure site traffic and visitor statistics.

## Log Files

As with most websites, our web server uses log files. Data automatically and customarily collected by log files includes IP (Internet protocol) addresses, browser types, Internet Service Providers (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform types, date/time stamps, and the number of clicks. Log files are used for website administration and to analyze trends, safeguard site security, show movement across pages, and gather broad demographic information. The data in log files is not linked to any personally identifiable information. All of our web server log files are automatically and permanently purged within seven days, thus fulfilling GDPR requirements.

## Cookies

Cookies are parcels of text commonly sent by a website to a browser, which may include an anony­mous unique identifier. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s options allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent by other sites.

We may use cookies to store functional information, such as your selected preferences when you visit our site, or other data to improve overall experience. Any cookies used on our site are anonymous and not personally identifiable to you. Linked sites may use cookies for logins, authen­tication, tracking, personal­ization, analytics, advertising, statistics or other purposes. Per standard web practice, cookies may be removed or disabled at any time via your browser settings.

## Email Information

You can sign up to receive our free monthly newsletter by providing your email address in the “Special Offers” or “[Free Books](https://prodesigntools.com/freebooks)” boxes. Our newsletter provides news and reviews on Adobe products, offers tips, techniques, and useful resources for using Adobe tools, and helps you save money on Adobe software with special discounts and coupon savings. In each newsletter there is a direct link to unsubscribe if you no longer wish to receive future mailings, and your information would be immediately and permanently deleted from our records. If you would otherwise like to modify or completely remove the email address stored in our subscriber list, please simply let us know via [our contact form](https://prodesigntools.com/contact-us.html). Your email address will never be sold, rented, or shared with any other parties, unless exceptionally required by law.

Our site’s content, including comments, is regularly indexed by search bots and, therefore, has the potential to be read, printed, and otherwise distributed around the world without the commenter’s consent. Within each comment, the publicly visible fields are Name, Website, and the content of the comment itself. Commenters agree not to hold our site liable for any unintended use of any comments they post. If you chose to post a comment on the site, you concurrently make certain concessions to publicity and, therefore, limit your personal privacy and that of your post. Nevertheless, we will never collect, sell, or otherwise distribute user information (such as email addresses) that isn’t otherwise publicly available on the site without the permission of the user(s). Just as our editors maintain the right to delete or edit any comment at any time for any reason they deem appropriate, any user may request his/her comments be deleted at any time for any reason s/he deems appropriate. Any requests for comment removal should be made via [our contact form](https://prodesigntools.com/contact-us.html).

## Partners & Affiliates

As official partners of Adobe, Amazon.com, Lynda.com, Kelby Training, and other companies, we may receive revenues from the display of affiliated links or banner advertising. For example, to help support the hosting and maintenance of this site, ProDesignTools.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate program designed to provide a means for sites to earn income by advertising and linking to [amazon.com](https://www.amazon.com/?tag=amzn-save-20).

As an authorized Amazon Associate, Adobe Affiliate, and member of other partner programs, we earn from qualifying purchases, at no additional cost to our readers. At least 10% of any net earnings from these efforts will be donated to Charity. However, we do not share any site data or any personally-identifying infor­mation with these partners or with any other entities.

All sponsored products, company names, brand names, trademarks and logos are the legal property of their respective owners. All rights reserved.

## Sharing Information with Third Parties

We do not ever sell, rent, or share website data or personal information with any other parties, unless exceptionally required by law.

## Commitment to Data Security

We take strong technical and organizational precautions to keep your personally identifiable information secure and confidential, to prevent any loss, misuse, or alteration. Only select authorized employees of our company have access to this information, which is safeguarded with AES encryption and strong password protection. All emails and newsletters from this site allow you to opt out of further mailings.

## Your Consent

By using our website, you consent the practices described in this privacy policy. These practices may be changed, but any changes will be posted at this location. You are encouraged to review the privacy policy whenever you visit our site to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.

Please see also our Terms of Use, which together govern our relationship with you in relation to this website.

## Contact

You can use our [Contact Form](https://prodesigntools.com/contact-us.html) to get in touch. Our mailing address is PO Box 1201, Princeton, NJ 08542-1201, USA

 _Thank you for visiting!_
